Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我叫Marco。
My name is Catherine.
我叫Catherine。
And today we have an intermediate level lesson talking about appearances.
今天我们要上一节中级课程，讨论关于外貌的话题。
That's right.
没错。
We are going to change or somebody wants to change their appearance and they're going
我们要改变，或者说有人想改变他们的外貌，他们打算
to have surgery.
做手术。
Well, before we get started, let's look at what kind of surgery they're having in today's
嗯，在我们开始之前，先来看看今天课程中他们做的是哪种手术，在今天的
vocabulary preview.
词汇预览部分。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So today we're going to be talking about plastic surgery specifically.
所以今天我们要专门讨论整形手术。
Plastic surgery.
整形手术。
So why plastic?
那为什么叫“整形”呢？
I have no idea.
我不知道。
I don't either.
我也不知道。
No.
不知道。
Well, basically, plastic surgery is, you know, surgery for your appearance, right?
嗯，基本上，整形手术就是，你知道，为了外貌做的手术，对吧？
It's not really for health reasons.
并不是出于健康原因。
That's right.
没错。
And sometimes they add things to you.
有时候他们会给你加东西。
Sometimes they take things away, but they're not for your health.
有时候他们会去掉一些东西，但都不是为了健康。
They're not for your heart or your lungs.
不是为了你的心脏或肺。
Right.
对。
It's for your appearance.
是为了你的外貌。
Yeah. and also called cosmetic surgery.
是的，也叫美容手术。
That's right.
没错。
And we'll be hearing that later.
我们后面会听到这个词。
But cosmetic means having to do with your appearance like cosmetics.
但cosmetic意思是与外貌有关的，就像化妆品一样。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
正是。
All right.
好的。
So we're going to be talking about this.
所以我们要讨论这个。
Let's listen to our dialogue for the first time and we'll be back.
让我们第一次听对话，听完再回来。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Look at me.
看看我。
I look so old.
我看起来好老。
I look as if I were 30.
我看起来像30岁一样。
Come on.
得了吧。
Stop being so vain.
别这么虚荣了。
You look great.
你看起来很棒。
You are beautiful.
你很漂亮。
Yes, I am.
是的，我是。
But I think it's time for some plastic surgery.
但我觉得是时候做点整形手术了。
I'm tired of these wrinkles and sagging skin.
我受够了这些皱纹和松弛的皮肤。
See?
看到了吗？
I don't see any wrinkles or sagging skin.
我没看到任何皱纹或松弛的皮肤。
You're 25.
你才25岁。
Stop being ridiculous.
别这么荒谬了。
Besides, I think that people who get Botox have facelifts or tummy tucks look weird.
而且，我觉得那些打肉毒杆菌、做拉皮或腹部除皱的人看起来很奇怪。
Doesn't look natural.
看起来不自然。
Whatever.
随便吧。
I think I'm going to get liposuction and a nose job and some breast implants as well.
我想我要做抽脂、隆鼻，还有隆胸。
I think you need to get brain surgery.
我觉得你需要做脑部手术。
I honestly don't think you need cosmetic surgery.
我真的不觉得你需要美容手术。
You look amazing.
你看起来美极了。
I thought you were my friend and would support me on this.
我以为你是我的朋友，会支持我。
I just want to feel better about myself and feel more attractive.
我只是想让自己感觉更好，更有吸引力。
You don't need plastic surgery to do that.
你不需要整形手术来做到这一点。
You're fine the way you are and you have guys drooling all over you.
你现在的样子就很好，而且有男人为你神魂颠倒。
Plus, plastic surgery hurts.
另外，整形手术很疼。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
I got my nose job, I was black and blue for a week.
我做了隆鼻，青肿了一个星期。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So yeah, they think this girl really wants to get this surgery.
所以，是的，他们认为这个女孩真的很想做这个手术。
But she doesn't seem to know why.
但她似乎不知道为什么。
She's just like, I'm in a bad mood.
她就像，我心情不好。
I want surgery.
我想做手术。
And that's the worst reason.
这是最糟糕的理由。
And it's pretty painful from what I hear.
而且据我所知，这相当痛苦。
Expensive and painful and potentially dangerous.
又贵又疼，还有潜在危险。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
But we can talk about that at the end.
但我们可以在最后讨论这个。
Alright.
好的。
So why don't we start with the words that we saw that are all related to surgery in
那我们为什么不从“语言要点”中看到的那些与手术相关的词开始呢？
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, well this first one might be the reason for surgery, not necessarily a kind of surgery.
好的，第一个可能是手术的原因，不一定是手术的类型。
If someone is vain.
如果某人很虚荣。
Okay, so if a person is vain, this is an adjective.
好的，所以如果一个人很虚荣，这是一个形容词。
That means that they are very, they care too much about their appearance, right?
意思是他们非常，他们太在意自己的外貌了，对吧？
Right.
对。
And they care so much that they only care about themselves.
而且他们在意到只关心自己。
So do I look good?
所以我看起来好看吗？
I love my face, my eyes.
我爱我的脸，我的眼睛。
I look so good.
我看起来太棒了。
So a person who is vain thinks very highly of themselves.
所以一个虚荣的人对自己评价很高。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
And well, this person I think wanted to get surgery as well because she said she had wrinkles.
嗯，我觉得这个人也想做手术，因为她说了她有皱纹。
Okay, wrinkles are little lines on your face.
好的，皱纹就是你脸上的细纹。
So maybe on your forehead or next to your mouth.
可能在前额或嘴角旁边。
And generally, when we get older, people get more and more of these.
一般来说，当我们变老时，人们会越来越多。
Right.
对。
And you have, even you have wrinkly skin when you're in the bathtub for too long and you
而且你甚至，当你在浴缸里泡太久时，皮肤会起皱，你
look in your hands, they look like raisins.
看看你的手，它们看起来像葡萄干。
You have wrinkly skin.
你的皮肤起皱了。
That's right.
没错。
Wrinkles are little lines in your skin.
皱纹就是你皮肤上的细纹。
All right.
好的。
And well, you have wrinkles as you said around your mouth and eyes.
嗯，就像你说的，皱纹出现在嘴和眼睛周围。
And sometimes under your eyes, you also have some sagging skin.
有时在眼睛下面，你也会有一些松弛的皮肤。
Or under your chin.
或者在下巴下面。
Under your chin as well, yeah.
下巴下面也是，是的。
That's right.
没错。
So sagging means coming down, means it's heavy.
所以sagging意思是下垂，意味着它很重。
It's like hanging.
就像挂下来一样。
Yeah.
是的。
Right.
对。
So sagging, something sags.
所以sagging，某物下垂。
It's heavy, it pulls down.
它很重，往下拉。
But if you have sagging skin, that means your skin is no longer tight.
但如果你有松弛的皮肤，那意味着你的皮肤不再紧致。
It's kind of loose and it hangs.
有点松垮，挂下来。
Falling off your face.
从脸上掉下来。
Okay.
好的。
And well, a new popular treatment that is not really surgery is this Botox.
嗯，一种新的流行疗法，其实不是手术，就是肉毒杆菌。
That's right.
没错。
So Botox is something that women and some men do every couple of months I think and
所以肉毒杆菌是女性，还有一些男性，每隔几个月会做的东西，我想，
they have to get shots.
他们得打针。
Right.
对。
They're like injections.
它们就像注射一样。
That's right.
没错。
And they tighten your skin.
它们能紧致你的皮肤。
And so you can get Botox in your face, your forehead or your eyes and it makes you look
所以你可以在脸上、额头或眼睛周围打肉毒杆菌，这会让你看起来
younger for a couple of months.
年轻几个月。
I've heard that they also put them in their lips to make them like fuller, right?
我听说他们也会把肉毒杆菌打在嘴唇上，让嘴唇更丰满，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And sometimes you can say that someone's had too much Botox because they can no longer
有时候你能看出某人肉毒杆菌打太多了，因为他们再也
smile or they can't stop smiling.
笑不出来，或者一直笑个不停。
Exactly.
正是。
And well, very related to this is also when people get a facelift.
嗯，与此非常相关的是，人们还会做面部拉皮手术。
Okay.
好的。
A facelift.
面部拉皮。
So basically it's that a doctor, a plastic surgeon will tighten the skin on your face
基本上就是医生，一位整形外科医生，会紧致你脸上的皮肤，
so he'll pull your eyes and the skin next to your ears to make your face look younger.
所以他会拉你的眼睛和耳朵旁边的皮肤，让你的脸看起来更年轻。
Right.
对。
So that's called a facelift.
所以那叫做面部拉皮。
So it's to kind of take away those wrinkles, right?
所以是为了消除那些皱纹，对吧？
Or the sagging skin.
或者下垂的皮肤。
Right.
对。
Lift means to pull up.
“拉皮”意思是向上提拉。
Right.
对。
It's the opposite of sag.
这是“下垂”的反义词。
Very good.
非常好。
Alright.
好了。
So this dialogue has a lot of rich vocabulary related to surgery.
所以这段对话有很多与手术相关的丰富词汇。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back with the second part of
那我们再听一遍对话，之后我们会回来继续第二部分
language takeaway to explain a little bit more.
语言要点讲解，进一步解释。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Look at me.
看看我。
I look so old.
我看起来好老。
I look as if I were 30.
我看起来像30岁似的。
Come on.
得了吧。
Stop being so vain.
别这么虚荣了。
You look great.
你看起来很棒。
You are beautiful.
你很漂亮。
Yes, I am.
是的，我是。
But I think it's time for some plastic surgery.
但我觉得是时候做点整形手术了。
I'm tired of these wrinkles and sagging skin.
我厌倦了这些皱纹和下垂的皮肤。
See?
看到了吗？
I don't see any wrinkles or sagging skin.
我没看到任何皱纹或下垂的皮肤。
You're 25.
你才25岁。
Stop being ridiculous.
别这么荒谬了。
Besides, I think that people who get Botox, have facelifts or tummy tucks look weird.
而且，我觉得那些打肉毒杆菌、做面部拉皮或腹部除皱的人看起来很奇怪。
It doesn't look natural.
看起来不自然。
Whatever.
随便吧。
I think I'm going to get liposuction and a nose job and some breast implants as well.
我想我要去做抽脂、隆鼻，还有隆胸。
I think you need to get brain surgery.
我觉得你需要做脑部手术。
I honestly don't think you need cosmetic surgery.
我真的不认为你需要做美容手术。
You look amazing.
你看起来美极了。
I thought you were my friend and would support me on this.
我以为你是我的朋友，会支持我这个决定。
I just want to feel better about myself and feel more attractive.
我只是想让自己感觉更好，更有吸引力。
You don't need plastic surgery to do that.
你不需要做整形手术来达到那个目的。
You're fine the way you are and you have guys drooling all over you.
你现在的样子就很好，而且你让男人们都为你神魂颠倒。
Plastic surgery hurts.
整形手术很疼。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
When I got my nose job, I was black and blue for a week.
我做完隆鼻手术后，整整一周都青一块紫一块的。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So what other surgical procedure is in store for us?
那么还有什么其他外科手术等着我们呢？
Well now the big ones.
嗯，现在是大的手术了。
So we've left the face and we're talking about the rest of the body.
我们已经离开了脸部，现在在谈论身体的其他部位。
The first one is a tummy tuck.
第一个是腹部除皱术。
Okay, so a tummy tuck.
好的，腹部除皱术。
What is that exactly?
那到底是什么？
Well, let's look at these two words by themselves because maybe tummy, people have heard before.
嗯，我们先单独看这两个词，因为“tummy”这个词，人们可能以前听过。
This is another way to say stomach.
这是“胃”的另一种说法。
Usually children say tummy.
通常小孩子会说“肚子”。
Right, my tummy hurts.
对，我肚子疼。
My tummy hurts and doctors, they'll say stomach.
我肚子疼，而医生会说“胃”。
But the name of this surgery is tummy tuck because tuck means to put in or to fold.
但这种手术的名字叫“腹部除皱”，因为“tuck”意思是塞进去或折叠。
And so my mom used to say tuck in your shirt.
所以我妈妈以前常说“把衬衫塞进去”。
You know when your shirt comes out of your pants and that means you put it back in.
你知道当你的衬衫从裤子里跑出来时，意思是把它塞回去。
Well a tuck means to fold your stomach under.
嗯，“tuck”在这里意思是把腹部折叠起来。
It means to make your stomach look smaller and they put staples or I think they sew you
意思是让肚子看起来更小，他们会用订书钉或者我想是把你缝起来。
up.
是的，他们把你缝起来。
Yeah, they sew you up.
嗯，他们把你缝起来。
It's pretty painful, right?
那很疼，对吧？
I've heard that.
我听说过。
Usually this is because somebody got a liposuction for example and that's our next word, liposuction.
通常这是因为某人做了抽脂手术，比如，那就是我们的下一个词，抽脂。
Okay, lipo, that's kind of fat, right?
好的，“lipo”是脂肪的意思，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
And suction means to pull like a vacuum.
而“suction”意思是像真空一样吸。
Right.
对。
So that's basically what they do.
所以基本上他们就是这么做的。
They open the person up and kind of use a sort of vacuum type device and suck all the
他们切开病人的身体，然后用一种类似真空的装置，把
fat out of the stomach or the balcony areas, you know, the love handles that are also called.
肚子或腰部赘肉（也叫“爱把手”）里的脂肪都吸出来。
And this way, they remove all this excess fat.
这样，他们就去除了所有多余的脂肪。
And because they do this, sometimes the skin, since it's been stretched out because you
因为他们这样做，有时皮肤，因为之前有点胖而被撑开，
were a little bit fat, they need to have a tummy tuck.
所以他们需要做腹部除皱术。
That means to hide the extra skin.
这意味着隐藏多余的皮肤。
The extra skin to kind of hide it.
多余的皮肤，把它藏起来。
So these two words, these two procedures actually go hand in hand because maybe if you're very
所以这两个词，这两个手术实际上是相辅相成的，因为如果你很
fat you get a liposuction but that doesn't solve your problem because now you have all
胖，你做了抽脂，但那并不能解决你的问题，因为现在你的
this sagging skin off your stomach.
肚子上全是下垂的皮肤。
That's right.
没错。
So you have to have a tummy tuck as well.
所以你还得做腹部除皱术。
Alright.
好的。
So yeah, very, very dangerous procedure I've heard as well, right?
是的，我听说这也是非常非常危险的手术，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
And they usually only do it with people who are very, very fat.
而且他们通常只对非常非常胖的人做这个手术。
That means dangerously fat.
也就是胖到危险的程度。
Because if you do it on a skinny person, you could really hurt them.
因为如果你对一个瘦子做这个手术，你真的会伤害到他们。
Yeah, of course, fat is also necessary for our bodies.
是的，当然，脂肪对我们的身体也是必要的。
Alright, so now moving back up to the face again, a very common procedure, I think one
好了，现在回到脸部，一个非常常见的手术，我想是
of the most common ones is a nose job.
最常见的手术之一，就是隆鼻。
A nose job.
隆鼻。
And so nose job is very colloquial.
“Nose job”是非常口语化的说法。
You'll hear this on the TV.
你会在电视上听到这个。
Nose job means to fix someone's nose, to change the shape or appearance of their nose.
“Nose job”意思是修复某人的鼻子，改变他们鼻子的形状或外观。
And so oftentimes people with really big noses want smaller noses.
所以通常鼻子很大的人想要小一点的鼻子。
And so the doctor will take some bone away and will put the skin back.
然后医生会取走一些骨头，再把皮肤放回去。
Yes, that's right.
是的，没错。
So this is called a nose job or formerly known as like a nose surgery, right?
所以这叫做隆鼻，或者正式名称是鼻子手术，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Rhinoplasty is the official name.
鼻整形术是正式名称。
And actually I've heard it's very painful because they have to break your nose before
实际上我听说这非常疼，因为他们必须先打断你的鼻子
they fix it.
才能修复它。
Exactly.
正是。
Wow.
哇。
I can't believe people do this.
真不敢相信有人会做这种事。
And well, one of the very common ones among women most likely is our breast implants.
嗯，女性中最常见的一种可能就是隆胸手术了。
That's right.
没错。
So breast implants, am I allowed to say boob job?
那么隆胸，我能说“胸部整形”吗？
Yeah, you can.
可以，你说吧。
Well, the very common phrase for this is boob job.
嗯，这个很常见的说法就是“胸部整形”。
Boob is a very colloquial term for breasts.
“Boob”是“乳房”的一个非常口语化的说法。
And breast implants are, well, an implant is something that you put inside something.
而隆胸植入物，嗯，植入物就是放进某样东西里的东西。
Okay.
好的。
And so a breast implant is a piece of silicone.
所以隆胸植入物是一块硅胶。
So it's like plastic, but it's more like a liquid plastic.
它像塑料，但更像是液态塑料。
Yeah.
嗯。
Just imagine like this big plastic bag with like gel, right?
想象一下，就像一个大塑料袋里面装着凝胶，对吧？
Inside of it.
在里面。
And they put that inside a woman's chest to make her breasts bigger.
然后他们把它放进女性的胸部，让她的乳房变大。
And so these are very, very popular surgeries, breast implants.
所以隆胸手术是非常非常流行的手术。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
I guess many models and many types, different types of women get breast implants.
我想很多模特和不同类型的女性都会做隆胸手术。
That's right.
没错。
And the verb there is to get.
这里的动词是“做”。
So she got breast implants.
所以她做了隆胸手术。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
Because they're things.
因为它们是东西。
Very good.
很好。
All right.
好了。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back to talk a
那我们最后再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一聊。
little bit more.
再聊一会儿。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Look at me.
看看我。
I look so old.
我看起来好老。
I look as if I were 30.
我看起来像30岁一样。
Come on.
别这样。
Stop being so vain.
别这么虚荣了。
You look great.
你看起来很棒。
You are beautiful.
你很漂亮。
Yes, I am.
是的，我是。
But I think it's time for some plastic surgery.
但我觉得是时候做点整容手术了。
I'm tired of these wrinkles and sagging skin.
我受够了这些皱纹和松弛的皮肤。
See?
看到了吗？
I don't see any wrinkles or sagging skin.
我没看到任何皱纹或松弛的皮肤。
You're 25.
你才25岁。
Stop being ridiculous.
别这么荒唐了。
Besides, I think that people who get Botox, have facelifts or tummy tucks look weird.
而且，我觉得那些打肉毒杆菌、做拉皮或腹部除皱的人看起来很奇怪。
It doesn't look natural.
看起来不自然。
Whatever.
随便吧。
I think I'm going to get liposuction and a nose job and some breast implants as well.
我想我要去做抽脂、隆鼻，还有隆胸。
I think you need to get brain surgery.
我觉得你需要做脑部手术。
I honestly don't think you need cosmetic surgery.
我真的不认为你需要整容手术。
You look amazing.
你看起来美极了。
I thought you were my friend and would support me on this.
我以为你是我的朋友，会支持我这个决定。
I just want to feel better about myself and feel more attractive.
我只是想让自己感觉更好，更有吸引力。
You don't need plastic surgery to do that.
你不需要整容手术来达到这个目的。
You're fine the way you are and you have guys drooling all over you.
你现在的样子就很好，而且有男人为你神魂颠倒。
Plus, plastic surgery hurts.
再说了，整容手术很疼。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
When I got my nose job, I was black and blue for a week.
我当初做隆鼻的时候，整整一周都是青一块紫一块的。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So, as you mentioned, all of these surgeries are very painful and very expensive, right?
那么，正如你提到的，所有这些手术都很疼，也很贵，对吧？
They are.
是的。
The plastic surgery industry is huge.
整容手术行业非常庞大。
I was just reading an article that said that re-dos are becoming very popular.
我刚读到一篇文章，说“返修”手术变得非常流行。
There are doctors who perform re-dos.
有专门做返修手术的医生。
That means-
也就是说——
To re-do a surgery.
重新做一次手术。
That's right.
没错。
They're fixing other surgeries because oftentimes people go in, they say, I want a nose job,
他们是在修复其他手术，因为很多时候人们去做手术，说“我想隆鼻”，
they get a nose job, and then it's not the nose they wanted.
他们做了隆鼻，结果不是他们想要的鼻子。
They have doctors now who specialize in fixing former surgeries.
现在有专门修复之前手术的医生。
Wow.
哇。
I've heard also a lot about the plastic surgery tourism industry where people get offered
我还听说过很多关于整容旅游行业的事情，人们会得到一个套餐，
a package, for example, to go to countries like Argentina where they have good doctors
比如去阿根廷这样的国家，那里有好医生，
and it's very inexpensive compared to the states to get plastic surgery.
而且和美国相比，整容手术非常便宜。
It's also popular now in Asia, I believe they're traveling to Hong Kong to get plastic surgery
现在在亚洲也很流行，我想人们会去香港做整容手术。
done.
做整容手术。
Interesting.
有意思。
Yeah, I know.
是啊，我知道。
But it's one of those things that if you have the money and you really feel that you want
但这是那种如果你有钱，而且真的想改善外貌的话——
to improve your appearance, then-
那就去做。
But is it an improvement?
但这真的是改善吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
It is.
是的。
It's a little fake.
有点假。
Yeah, it is a little bit fake.
嗯，是有点假。
Like, for example, but it does help people with their self-confidence, right?
比如，但它确实能帮助人们建立自信，对吧？
Sometimes, for example, with the case of breast implants, some women feel very, very self-conscious
有时候，比如在隆胸的情况下，一些女性会对自己胸部较小感到非常不自在。
about them having smaller breasts.
她们想要更大的胸部，然后感觉更自信、更快乐，诸如此类。
They want to get bigger breasts and they feel more confident, happier, and stuff like this.
I guess if it helps and if you really want it, everyone's to their own.
我想如果这有帮助，而且你真的想要，那就各随己愿吧。
Well, I'm curious what our users think about this.
嗯，我很好奇我们的用户对此怎么看。
Have you had plastic surgery?
你做过整容手术吗？
Would you like to have plastic surgery?
你想做整容手术吗？
Let us know on our website, EnglishPod.com.
在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上告诉我们吧。
Right.
对。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候见。
Until next time.
下次再见。
Bye.
拜拜。
Thank you.
谢谢。